injuryboard.com 2012-10-20

# Injuryboard.com | Privacy Statement, Disclaimer, and Terms of Use

The Legal Examiner is a licensee of the [TRUSTe Privacy Program](http://www.truste.org/ "TRUSTe"). TRUSTe is an independent, organization whose mission is to build user’s trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This Privacy Statement applies to the website [www.legalexaminer.com](http://www.legalexaminer.com/). The Legal Examiner aims to be your most trusted guide to personal injury legal, insurance and medical concerns on the Internet. In order to earn your trust, we at The Legal Examiner would like to inform you of our policies and procedures as they relate to your privacy. Because The Legal Examiner wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/ "TRUSTe"), an outside and independent reviewer.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact The Legal Examiner Support. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with The Legal Examiner to help resolve your concerns.

First and foremost, The Legal Examiner, Injury Board and its management are intimately aware of, and have the utmost respect for, your privacy. The confidential nature of your communications with The Legal Examiner, Injury Board and our member firms will always be respected.

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

You can access information on The Legal Examiner without creating an account on our site. If you choose to create a member account on our site, we collect your personally identifiable information such as your name and email address to create your account. We provide you the option of making your user profile “public” or “private." Please be aware that should you choose to have a public profile, your account information will be visible to other users of this site and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to disclose in your public profile. When you set your profile to “Private,” none of your personally identifiable information is viewable by the other users of this site. You can always adjust your profile preferences by accessing your account and selecting to “Edit Profile.”

We use your account information to provide you with access to the forums area as well, which require a user to be registered prior to posting information. You should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information that you choose to submit in these forums.

We also collect your full name, email, phone number and zip code when you select to use our “E-mail an Attorney” forms on The Legal Examiner to have a question answered using our site. We use this collected information to service your request for an attorney by submitting your information to one of the lawyers acting as a service provider on our site. This information is used for no other purposes other than to fulfill your request. We also use this personally identifiable information to process “Membership Inquiries” submitted by attorneys on our site. We do not share your information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

**SERVICE PROVIDERS**

The Legal Examiner is neither a lawyer referral service, nor a law firm. The Legal Examiner is an information platform that allows users to access information on our site provided by Injury Board, its members, and third parties to service your requests for information. Most information is provided by Law Firms with expertise in legal issues pertaining to personal injury law and related matters. The law firms acting as service providers on our site are not authorized to use your personally identifiable information for any purposes other than to fulfill the service requests you make on our site while [“Contacting an attorney”](http://members.injuryboard.org/ "Contacting an attorney") or accessing information presented by attorneys in their blogs.

As is true of all licensed attorneys, a duty of confidentiality governs the attorneys associated with Injury Board. State bar associations from around the United States enforce this duty of confidentiality. The duty of confidentiality prohibits attorneys from revealing your confidential information to others. The American Bar Association defines the duty of confidentiality as follows:

__Rule 1.6 Confidentiality of Information__

_(a) A lawyer shall not reveal information relating to representation of a client unless the client consents after consultation, except for disclosures that are impliedly authorized in order to carry out the representation, and except as stated in paragraph (b)._

_(b) A lawyer may reveal such information to the extent the lawyer reasonably believes necessary:_

_(1) To prevent the client from committing a criminal act that the lawyer believes is likely to result in imminent death or substantial bodily harm; or_

_(2) to establish a claim or defense on behalf of the lawyer in a controversy between the lawyer and the client, to establish a defense to a criminal charge or civil claim against the lawyer based upon conduct in which the client was involved, or to respond to allegations in any proceeding concerning the lawyer's representation of a client._

**BLOG DISCLOSURE**

If you post to a bulletin board, blog, or post a comment on this website, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information that you choose to submit in these public forums.

**TESTIMONIAL DISCLOSURE**

We occasionally provide user testimonials on our web site from users who have submitted their experiences with The Legal Examiner or Injury Board, as well as posting personally identifiable information such as name, phone number and email of attorneys and legal staff of member law firms. We obtain explicit consent prior to posting testimonials on our site. Any personally identifiable information you choose to post within your testimonial may be used by other users of this site to contact you. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to post to our website with your testimonial.

**COOKIES**

When you interact with the site, we try to make that experience simple and meaningful. When you visit our site, our Web server sends a cookie to your computer. Cookies are files that Web browsers place on a computer's hard drive and are used to indicate whether you have visited the site previously.

**Choices about Cookies:** You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) If you reject all cookies, you will still be able to use our site.

**Our Practices Regarding Cookies:** We use cookies for a number of purposes, including to: access your account information when you "sign in," so that we can provide you with customized content; keep track of preferences you specify while you are using our services; estimate and report our total audience size and traffic; and conduct research to improve our content and services.

Third Party Cookies: We may from time to time engage third parties to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from visitors to our site to help us administer our site and improve its quality. Such third parties may use cookies to help track visitor behavior. Such cookies will not be used to associate individual website visitors to any personally identifiable information. All data collected by such third parties on our behalf are only used to provide us with information on Site usage and is not shared with any other third parties for their promotional purposes.

Any and all emails sent out from The Legal Examiner are in relation to a service you have requested. We may contact you with notifications of site updates or technical issues as necessary. These emails are generally not promotional in nature & consequently, you cannot opt-out of receiving them.

**LEGAL DISCLOSURE**

We may be legally obligated to disclose information to the government or to third parties under certain circumstances, such as illegal activity on our site. The Legal Examiner reserves the right to release personal information to its service providers, law enforcement or other government officials in response to a formal request in a civil action, when complying with a court order, subpoena or judicial proceeding as The Legal Examiner in our sole and absolute discretion, deems necessary or appropriate.

We may also provide Aggregated Information to third parties. Such information will not include personal information of any customer or visitor.

In the event of the sale, acquisition or merger of some or all of The Legal Examiner’s assets, your personal information would likely be among the transferred assets. Should such an event occur, we shall notify you via email of the transfer along with your options as to how your information is used henceforth.

**CORRECTING & UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION**

You can access your account information on our site by logging into your account & accessing the “Member Area” of the site. From here, you can adjust your account settings and change your preferences as you see fit. To delete your information from our site including your account information, you can contact us.

**THIRD PARTY SITES**

The site contains links to other web sites. The Legal Examiner is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other web sites. Customers and visitors will need to check the policy statement of these others web sites to understand their policies. Customers and visitors who access a linked site may be disclosing their private information. It is the responsibility of the user to keep such information private and confidential.

**SECURITY AND DATA STORAGE**

Our Site has considerale security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the personal information and Data under our control. We host the site in a secure server environment that uses firewalls, intrusion monitoring and other industry-standard technology to help prevent interference or access from outside intruders.

**CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT**

The Legal Examiner may update this Statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Statement, we will notify you in this Statement, by email or by a notice posted on the home page of the Site.

QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS POLICY 

If you have any questions about this Statement or the practices of this Site, please contact us at:

The Legal Examiner,  
209 S. Howard Avenue   
Tampa, FL 33606

The Legal Examiner is the leading personal injury legal site for consumers. However, The Legal Examiner is neither a law firm nor a legal referral service, nor a doctor's office. As such, this site should not be used as a substitute for an attorney's advice or a medical doctor's diagnosis. The Legal Examiner provides general legal, health, injury and medical information. However, our website does not provide specific medical or legal advice for an individual's specific matter or concern. Instead, the information we provide is general in nature, and you are encouraged to speak with an [Injury Board member attorney](http://members.injuryboard.org/) regarding your specific legal questions.

If you are concerned with a specific medical condition, we urge you to seek a doctor's advice. We cannot provide such medical advice to you. Additionally, if you have a specific legal problem, we encourage you to contact an attorney. As laws vary from state to state and change over time, only a licensed attorney can provide you with specific legal advice. Furthermore, please be conscious of Statutes of Limitation in your state, the time periods within which you are allowed to bring a claim. There are sometime exceptions to these time limits depending on special circumstances, so consult with a lawyer in your state if you have questions about Statutes of Limitations.

The Legal Examiner allows you to contact one of our member firms free of charge. By contacting a member firm, you have not entered into an attorney/client relationship. Such a relationship can only be established after both parties have signed a written document. Injury Board member firms sponsor the efforts to create, maintain, and provide content for The Legal Examiner so that users of the site may access important safety, legal and injury information that may be unavailable or difficult to find elsewhere. Should you enter into an attorney/client relationship with an The Legal Examiner member firm, The Legal Examiner does not receive any referral fee from the member form, nor does it receive any portion of the attorneys' or law firms' fees upon resolution of a matter.

A great deal of the information provided on this website is provided by our members and other third parties, and these parties are responsible for the contents of the information they have provided. The Legal Examiner is not responsible for the actions and/or inactions of Injury Board member firms. Although Injury Board seeks only members who are competent, ethical, and experienced, we are unable to guarantee your satisfaction with any Injury Board member's answers or services provided.

Furthermore, you are not required or obligated to retain the services of our member firms in order to use this website. Certain state bar associations may consider an The Legal Examiner membership to be a form of advertising, and require that we inform our users that the hiring of a lawyer is an important decision that should not be based solely on advertisement. Such a decision should only be made after the review and careful consideration of a firm's experience and qualifications.

While we make every reasonable effort to provide useful, timely and accurate information, we cannot guarantee the correctness of this information, nor can we guarantee that we carry information on every conceivable injury subject. In addition, Although we closely monitor government agency initiated product recalls, alerts and warnings, we may from time to time be unaware of certain recalls and safety alerts, and encourage you to be vigilant in your research and use of information provided by government regulatory agencies such as the [FDA.](http://www.fda.gov/ "FDA")

**MEDICAL DISCLAIMER**

This site is not designed to and does not provide medical advice, professional diagnosis, opinion, treatment or services or otherwise engage in the practice of medicine, to you or to any other individual. Please use this information to help in your conversation with your physician. This is general information and always seek the advice of your physician or other qualified health provider with any questions you may have regarding a medical condition. Never disregard or delay seeking professional medical advice or treatment because of content found on the Website (or newsletter).

The Legal Examiner is the property of Claris Law, LLC. Copying, distributing or otherwise using the information contained on the site is strictly prohibited. By using The Legal Examiner, you agree that under no circumstances will The Legal Examiner, Claris Law, LLC, its affiliates, or any lawyer or law firm participating in this site be responsible for (1) any information contained on, in or omitted from the site, (2) any person's reliance on any such information, whether or not the information is correct, current or complete, (3) the consequences of any action you or any other person takes or fails to take, whether or not based on information provided by, or as a result of, the use of the site. The Legal Examiner, Claris Law, LLC, or its affiliates also have no responsibility for (4) any person's satisfaction with any lawyer or law firm, whether relating to the lawyer's or law firm's competence, diligence, or otherwise (5) the results of any advice given by, or representation from, any lawyer or law firm, or (6) the failure or refusal of any lawyer or law firm to respond to you or consult with you.
